A Guide to the Paul C. Nagel Papers, n.d.
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Paul C. Nagel Papers, n.d.
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 255
25 linear feet
Paul C. Nagel
Administrative Information
Access
The correspondence files are restricted until 2012 unless the researcher has written permission from Dr. Nagel or his executor.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated to the Department by Dr. Nagel in insallments beginning in 1987.
Biographical/Historical Information
Paul C. Nagel was a historian.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains materials relating to Dr. Nagel's professional and literary career including teaching, administration and drafts of his books. The bulk of the collection relates to the development, research and publication of Nagel's work on the Adams and Lee families.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically within each series.
Organization
Series I--Lecture and Teaching Materials (-)
Series II--Descent from Glory (-)
Series III--Other Papers, Books and Speeches by Nagel (-)
Series IV--Articles by Others sent to PCN (-)
Series V--Reviews (-)
Series VI--Correspondence (-)
Series VII--The Adams Women (-)
Series VIII--George Caleb Bingham (-)
Series IX--Lee Book (-); Restricted Correspondence (-)
Contents List
- Series I-Lecture and Teaching Materials
  - Background Readings for History 452 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Backup History 20 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - History II: Lectures 1-28 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - History II: Syllabus and Tests (Box-folder 1.4)
  - History 20: Lectures (Box-folder 1.5)
  - History 98: Lectures (Box-folder 1.6)
  - History 98: Materials and Tests (Box-folder 1.7)
  - History 351: Lectures 1-15 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - History 351: Lectures 16-26 (Box 1.9)
  - History 351: Lectures 27-38 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - History 351: Syllabus and Tests (Box-folder 2.2)
  - History 352 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - History 451: Seminar (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Notes: Ante Bellum (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Notes: Recent American History (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Research Paper for History 208-210 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Seminar Materials: Adams Family (Box-folder 2.8)
- Series II- Descent from Glory
  - Early Draft of the Background (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 1
  - Early Draft of Chapter 2 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 3 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 4 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 5 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 6 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 7 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 8 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 9 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 10 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 11 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 12 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 13 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 14 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 15 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 16 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 17 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 18 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Early Observations-general (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Henry's Retreat (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Brook's Zeal (Box-folder 4.9)
  - A Last Reunion (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Adams-Early Stage (Box-folder 4.11)
  - John Quincy Adams (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Notes for John Adams' Family (Box-folder 4.13)
  - Background (Box-folder 4.14)
  - Some Words to the Reader (Box-folder 4.15)
  - A New Generation of Troubles (Box-folder 4.16)
  - Acknowledgement (Box-folder 4.17)
  - Contents (Box-folder 4.18)
  - Permissions (Box-folder 4.19)
  - Sources (Box-folder 4.20)
  - Notes for Chapters 1 and 2 (Box-folder 4.21)
  - Introduction (Box-folder 4.22)
  - First Chapter Drafts-Adams (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Chapter 2 Drafts (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Chapter 3 Drafts (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Chapter 4 Drafts (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Chapter 5 Drafts (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Chapter 6 Drafts (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Chapter 7 Drafts (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Chapter 8 Drafts (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Chapter 9 Drafts (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Chapter 10 Drafts (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Chapter 11 Drafts (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Chapter 12 Drafts (Box-folder 5.12)
  - Chapter 13 Drafts (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Chapter 14 Drafts (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Conclusion (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Postscript (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Chapter 1 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Chapter 3 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Chapter 10 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Chapter 11 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Chapter 12 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Chapter 13 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Chapter 14 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Chapter 15 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Chapter 16 (Box-folder 6.14)
  - Chapter 17 (Box-folder 6.15)
  - Chapter 18 (Box-folder 6.16)
  - Comments from Rod Kellar on Descent from Glory (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Revised Page Proof Copy-1 of 3 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Revised Page Proof Copy-2 of 3 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Revised Page Proof Copy-3 of 3 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Manuscript, 1-150 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Manuscript, 151-300 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Manuscript, 301-450 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Manuscript, 451-600 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Manuscript, 601-693 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Galley Proofs (Box 9)
  - John Adams Family (Box 10)
- Series III-Other Papers, Books, and Speeches by Nagel
  - Abigail: The Adams Matriarch (Box-folder 11.1)
  - Adams Fourth Generation--Notes (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Brooks Adams After Half a Century (Box-folder 11.3)
  - Charles Francis Adams and the Old House (Box-folder 11.3(1))
  - The Era of Good Feeling: Foundation for Disunion-carbon copy of doctoral dissertation (Box-folder 11.4)
  - The Era of Good Feeling: Foundation for Disunion-thesis to graduate faculty of the University of Minnesota (Box-folder 11.5)
  - Hells Canyon Dam (Box-folder 12.1)
  - How Death Approached Henry Adams (Box-folder 12.2)
  - John Adams in Old Age (Box-folder 12.3)
  - John Tyler as Congressman and Senator-thesis to graduate faculty of the University of Minnesota (Box-folder 12.4)
  - Louisa: the Story of Henry Adams Sister (Box-folder 12.5)
  - Louisa Catherine: The Adams Mother (Box-folder 12.6)
  - Massachusetts Historical Society Symposium (Box-folder 12.7)
  - Miscellaneous bibliographies (Box-folder 12.8)
  - Miscellaneous speeches (Box-folder 12.9)
  - Missouri: A Bicentennial History-final copy with various readers mutations (Box-folder 12.10)
  - New York Venerates the Union: A Forgotten Bryan Poem (Box-folder 12.11)
  - Notes on American History (Box-folder 12.12)
  - Notes on the American West (Box-folder 13.1)
  - Notes on History of the South (Box-folder 13.2)
  - Notes on Various History classes (Box-folder 13.3)
  - The Pilgrimage of John Quincy Adams (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Report to the Faculty of Eastern Kentucky State College/Reports of the Study Committee on Preparation of a Salary Research Paper Written for Miss Turpis's Class (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Research Paper Written for Mrs. Tyler's Class (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Research Paper Written for Professor D. H. Wilson's Class (Box-folder 13.7)
  - Research Paper Written for Professor H. N. Smith's Class (Box-folder 13.8)
  - The Restless Old Age of Charles Francis Adams II (Box-folder 13.9)
  - The Sectional Spirit of the Early Tariffs (Box-folder 13.10)
  - Twice to the Fair Chicago History Magazine (Box-folder 13.11)
  - What About Henry Adams Sister? (Box-folder 13.12)
  - The Young John Adams (Box-folder 13.13)
- Series IV-Articles People Have Written and Sent to Nagel
  - XVII Siecle-Jean Charron (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Agricola versus Aristedes: James Monroe, John Marshall and the Genet Affair in Virginia-Harry Ammon (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Alexander Bickel and the Post-Realist Constitution-Edward Purcell (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Alexander Spotswood and the Business of Empire By Bruce P. Lenman, Colonial Williamsburg (Box-folder 14.3(1))
  - Alleged Palatinates of Norman England-James Alexander (Box-folder 14.4)
  - American Civil War as a Norman England-James Alexander (Box-folder 14.4)
  - American Civil War as a Constitutional Crisis-Arthur (Box-folder 14.5)
  - American Nationalism and the Image of Europe (1914-1945) Daniel J. Boorstin (Box-folder 14.6)
  - American Revolution Twice Recalled-Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 14.7)
  - American Women and the American Character-David Potter (Box-folder 14.8)
  - Another Howells Anarchist Letter-John W. Ward (Box-folder 14.9)
  - Aspects of the National Identity-Merrill D. Peterson (Box-folder 14.10)
  - Bee: A Tour of Crotchet Castle-Charles Mullett (Box-folder 14.11)
  - Big Things Require Time to Mature: Adamses and the Massachusetts Historical Society-Malcolm Freiberg (Box-folder 14.12)
  - Biological Retrospect-Peter Medawar (Box-folder 14.13)
  - Black Iron workers and the Slave Insurrection Panic of 1856-Charles B. Dew (Box-folder 14.14)
  - Book of the Wiles of Women-John Keller (Box-folder 14.15)
  - Britons in New York on Brother Jonathan's Birthday Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 14.16)
  - Broad Horizons-A.L. Burt (Box-folder 14.17)
  - Bryant's Use of the American Past-Donald A. Ringe (Box-folder 14.18)
  - Burger Court: A Judicial Nonet Plays the Enigma Variations-Dick Howard (Box-folder 14.19)
  - Central Powers and Second Turkish Alliance, 1915 Gerard E. Silberstein (Box-folder 14.20)
  - Challanges and Opportunities in Writing State and Local History-Michael Kammen (Box-folder 14.21)
  - Changing Nature of America's Civil Religion-Sydney Ahlstrom (Box-folder 14.22)
  - Chiaroscuro as an Artistic Device in Cooper's Fiction-Donald A. Ringe (Box-folder 14.23)
  - Co-Responsibilities of American Booksellers and Publishers-Carl Kroch (Box-folder 14.24)
  - Delawarean's View of Russia in 1816-Stanley Zyzniewski (Box-folder 14.25)
  - Deception of Exotic Animals in Cantiga XXIX of the Cantigas de Santa Maria-John E. Keller (Box-folder 14.26)
  - Early American Emeriti: A Symposium of Experience and Evaluation (Box-folder 14.27)
  - End and a Beginning: Reflections on Sydney Allstrom's Religious History of the American People and the Future of Sociologically-Informed inquiry into Religion in American Life-John Lankford (Box-folder 14.28)
  - England and America in the Schoolbooks of the Republic, 1783-1861-J. Merton England (Box-folder 14.29)
  - Epitaph for Slavery-Bennett H. Wall (Box-folder 14.30)
  - Failure on the Last Frontier: A Family Chronicle Gilbert C. Fite (Box-folder 14.31)
  - Fifteen American Authors Before 1900-Earl Harbert (Box-folder 14.32)
  - Folklore as History: Russian Byliny and Istoricheski Pesni-Russell Zguta (Box 14.33)
  - Forty-Eighth Annual Meeting of the Southern Historical Association-Robert W. Johanssen (Box-folder 14.34)
  - From Boundlessness to Consolidation-John Higham (Box-folder 14.35)
  - From Jefferson to Emerson-Merrill D. Peterson (Box-folder 14.36)
  - Genet Mission and the Development of American Political Parties-Harry Ammon (Box-folder 14.37)
  - George Washington: American Moses-Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 14.38)
  - George William Brown and His Influence on the Johns Hopkins University-Hugh Hawkins (Box-folder 14.39)
  - Glorious Departure of the American Patriarch-Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 14.40)
  - Historians Join the March on Montgomery-Walter Johnson (Box-folder 14.41)
  - Holman Hamilton-James A. Ramage (Box-folder 14.42)
  - Individualism Today-John W. Ward (Box-folder 14.43)
  - Inside of History-John W. Ward (Box-folder 14.44)
  - Jefferson Monument at the University of Missouri-William Peden (Box-folder 15.1)
  - John Dickinson at the Federal Constitutional Convention James H. Huston (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Joseph Leconte's Evolutional Idealism: A Lamarckian View of Cultural History-Lester Stephens (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Justification and Moral Reasoning-Kai Nielsen (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Keyserling's Landpartie-Wayne Wonderly (Box-folder 15.5)
  - LR Scale Manual-Peter C. Hoffer (Box-folder 15.6)
  - Liberty Tree: A Symbol of American Patriots-Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 15.7)
  - Lincoln and the South in 1860-Robert W. Johannsen (Box-folder 15.8)
  - Litigation Society?-A.E. Dick Howard (Box-folder 15.9)
  - Long Lost Returns: The Candidates and Their Totals in Louisiana's Secession Election-Charles B. Dew (Box-folder 15.10)
  - Making of a Railroad President: Milton Hannibal Smith and the L and N-Mary K. Tachau (Box-folder 15.11)
  - Meaning of Lindergh's Flight-John W. Ward (Box-folder 15.12)
  - Monroe Doctrine: Domestic Politics or National Decision? Harry Ammon (Box-folder 15.13)
  - Multum in Parvo: Gilbert White of Selbourne-Charles F. Mullett (Box-folder 15.14)
  - New Era for the United States: Americans and the War with Mexico-Robert W. Johannsen (Box-folder 15.15)
  - Newington Green: A Study of a Dissenting Community-Carl Cone (Box-folder 15.16)
  - Not So Long Ago--Reminisce and Review-Gerald C. Fite (Box-folder 15.17)
  - Novelist Confronts Clio-Charles F. Mullett (Box-folder 15.18)
  - Place to Stand-Ernest S. Osgood (Box-folder 15.19)
  - Poems About Lincoln-John A. Abbott (Box-folder 15.20)
  - Private Business and Private Education-John W. Ward (Box-folder 15.21)
  - Problem of Constitutionalism in American Culture Michael Kammen (Box-folder 15.22)
  - Providence and the American Past-Robert P. Hay (Box-folder 15.23)
  - Psychohistory and Empirical Group Affiliation-Peter C. Hoffer (Box-folder 15.24)
  - Quest for Useful Knowledge in Eighteenth-Century America-Meyer Reinhold (Box-folder 15.25)
  - Ranulf III of Chester-An Outlaw of Legend?-James Alexander (Box-folder 15.26)
  - Reason and Morality-Kai Neilsen (Box-folder 15.27)
  - Recent American Past vs. H.R. 4347: Historians's Dilemma-Walter Rundell, Jr. (Box-folder 15.28)
  - Recovery of American Religious History: Developments Since 1964-John Lankford (Box-folder 15.29)
  - Regionalist Painting and American Studies-Kenneth Labudde (Box-folder 15.30)
  - Scholar's Guide-Joseph Jones and John Keller (Box-folder 15.31)
  - Shadow of a Coming War-Robert V. Bruce (Box-folder 15.32)
  - Sixty-Third Annual Meeting of the Organization of American Historians-Robert Johannsen (Box-folder 15.33)
  - Skomorokhi: the Russian Minstrel-Entertainers Russel Zguta (Box-folder 15.34)
  - Social History: A Nation Announcing Itself-Phillip Jordan (Box-folder 15.35)
  - Some reflections on Freedom-John W. Ward (Box-folder 15.36)
  - Southern Commemoration of the Nation's One Hundredth Birthday-W. Burlie Brown (Box-folder 15.37)
  - Southern History from Local Sources: A Survey of Graduate History Training-Walter Rundell, Jr. (Box-folder 15.38)
  - Southernization of the American Revolution-R.R. Rapp (Box-folder 15.39)
  - Special Program in American Civilization at Princeton John W. Ward (Box-folder 15.40)
  - State Sovereignty and Slavery-Arthur Bestor (Box-folder 15.41)
  - Stephen A. Douglas and the South-Robert W. Johannsen (Box-folder 15.42)
  - Sub-Group Formation in the Constitutional Convention S. Sidne Ulmer (Box-folder 15.43)
  - Thomas Jefferson and the Beginnings of American Citizenship-Merrill D. Peterson (Box-folder 15.44)
  - What's in a Name?-Alan Simpson (Box-folder 15.45)
  - Who Was Benjamin Franklin?-John W. Ward (Box-folder 15.46)
  - Who Won the Secession Election in Louisiana? Charles Dew (Box-folder 15.47)
  - Witchcraft Trials in 17th Century Russia-Russell Zguta (Box-folder 15.48)
  - Writing of American History in the 1960s-John Lankford (Box-folder 15.49)
- Series V-Reviews
  - Adams Manuscript Comments from Rod Kellar (Box-folder 16.1)
  - Advertisements, Reviews for Descent From Glory (Box-folder 16.1(2))
  - Articles by Paul C. Nagel (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Blesser, Huntington, Faust Reviews (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Book Reviews by Paul C. Nagel (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Book Reviews (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Clover Review (Box-folder 16.6)
  - Comments on SHA Paper (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Cunliffe Book Review (Box-folder 16.8)
  - Edward Chalfant Review (Box-folder 16.9)
  - HA Review (Box-folder 16.10)
  - History Review Format and Celia Moss Review (Box-folder 16.11)
  - Lee Review (Box-folder 16.12)
  - New England Quarterly Review (Box-folder 16.13)
  - Review of Henry Adams' Letters (Box-folder 16.14)
  - Various Book Reviews (Box-folder 16.15)
- Series VI-Correspondence
  - Adams, Henry's Hat to Smithsonian 1988 (Box-folder 17.1)
  - American Heritage Publishing Co. 1984-1987 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - American Studies Association (Box-folder 17.3)
  - Americana Magazine 1988 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - Americana Magazine- The Adamses at Home (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Author's Guild, Inc. (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Reprint Series in History 1962, 1965, 1967 (Box-folder 17.7)
  - Book of the Month Club 1986 (Box-folder 17.8)
  - Book of the Month Club Talk (Box-folder 17.9)
  - Center for Research Libraries Board 1966-1968 (Box-folder 17.10)
  - Challinor, Joan R. Correspondence 1986 (Box-folder 17.11)
  - Challinor, Joan R. Paper 1986 (Box-folder 17.12)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation 1984-1986 (Box-folder 17.13)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation 1987-1988 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Commonwealth Club Membership 1981 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Cornell Enterprise Magazine-Fall 1986 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Earth City Event (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Election of 1842: A Reconstruction Correspondence (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Harris, Wilhelmina S. Miscellaneous (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Hollinshead, Bryan 1987-1988 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - Illinois Quarterly-Spring 1982 (Box-folder 18.8)
  - Jacobson, Timothy Correspondence (Box-folder 18.9)
  - Kentucky Colonel 1984 (Box-folder 18.10)
  - Lectures (Box-folder 18.11)
  - Library of Congress-Biography (Box-folder 18.12)
  - Massachusetts Historical Society Membership (Box-folder 18.13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Monticello-Stratford Summer Seminar 1985 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - Nashville Seminar (Box-folder 19.4)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box-folder 19.5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Travel (Box-folder 19.6)
  - NEH Grant-Sabbatical Alternatives (Box-folder 19.7)
  - Nationalism (Box-folder 19.8)
  - New York Public Library Luncheon (Box-folder 19.9)
  - Northeastern University Press (Box-folder 19.10)
  - Olson, James C. 1986-1987 (Box-folder 19.11)
  - One Nation Lndivisable (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Organization of American Historians (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Oxford Editorial Revision (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Oxford University Press-Adams Family (Box-folder 20.4)
  - Oxford University Press (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Oxford University Press (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Parsons, Lynn H. 1975 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - Pilgrim Society (Box-folder 20.8)
  - Roanoke TV (Box-folder 20.9)
  - Rusk, Dean (Box-folder 20.10)
  - Speeches and Writings (Box-folder 20.11)
  - Sacred Trust (Box-folder 21.1)
  - USIS Correspondence 21.2 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - USIS Trip to Germany (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Subseries A--Restricted Correspondence
    - Correspondence 1946-1954 (Box A)
    - Correspondence 1955-1960 (Box A)
    - Correspondence 1961-1964 (Box A)
    - Correspondence 1965-1966 (Box A)
    - Correspondence 1967 (Box A)
    - Correspondence 1968 (Box B)
    - Correspondence 1969 (Box B)
    - Correspondence 1970 (Box B)
    - Correspondence 1971 (Box B)
    - Correspondence 1972 (Box B)
    - Correspondence 1973 (Box C)
    - Correspondence 1974 (Box C)
    - Correspondence 1975 (Box C)
    - Correspondence 1976 (Box C)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1977 (Box C)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1977 (Box C)
    - Correspondence 1978 (Box D)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1979 (Box D)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1979 (Box D)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1980 (Box D)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1980 (Box D)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1981 (Box E)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1981 (Box E)
    - Correspondence 1982 (Box E)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1983 (Box E)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1983 (Box E)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1984 (Box F)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1984 (Box F)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1985 (Box F)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1985 (Box F)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1986 (Box F)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1986 (Box G)
    - Correspondence (January-May) 1987 (Box G)
    - Correspondence (June-December) 1987 (Box G)
    - Correspondence (January-May) 1988 (Box G)
    - Correspondence (June-December) 1988 (Box G)
    - Correspondence (January-May) 1989 (Box H)
    - Correspondence (June-December) 1989 (Box H)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1990 (Box H)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1990 (Box H)
    - Correspondence (January-June) 1991 (Box H)
    - Correspondence (July-December) 1991 (Box H)
    - Correspondence--Adams Books 1971-1988 (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Adams (Henry) Book and Review, n.d. 1988-1989 (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Adames Women Promotion, n.d. 1987 (Box I)
    - Correspondence--American Association of State and Local History (Box I)
    - Correspondence--American Heritage Publishing (Box I)
    - Correspondence-- Americana Magazine (October) 1990 (Box I)
    - Correspondence-- Americana Magazine (Lee Article) (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Bingham, George Caleb 1987-1990 (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Bingham, George Caleb Dinner (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Bingham, George Caleb Notes (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Boston Athenaeum 1990 (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Chelsea House Publishers (Box I)
    - Correspondence--Church 1979-1991 (Box J)
    - Correspondence--Colonial Williamsburg 1984-1988 (Box J)
    - Correspondence--Colonial Williamsburg 1988-1994 (Box J)
    - Correspondence--Colonial Williamsburg Education (Box J)
    - Correspondence--Cutts Collection (Box J)
    - Correspondence--Danch and Abrams (Lee Travel), n.d. 1989-1990 (Box J)
    - Correspondence-- Descent from Glory 1982-1983 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Descent from Glory(April-December) 1983 (Box K)
    - Correspondence-- Descent from Glory 1984-1987 (Box K)
    - Correspondence-- Extraordinary Lives 1985-1986 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Herman vs. Board of Regents (Georgia) 1979-1983 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Houghton-Mifflin 1989-1990 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Kellar, James Rodney 1960, 1979-1982 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Kellar, James Rodney 1983-1985 (Box K)
    - Correspondence--Kellar, James Rodney (Lee Book) (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Kellar, James Rodney 1986-1988 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Kellar, James Rodney 1989-1991 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Kentucky Arts Commission 1965-1969 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Loyola College 1991 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Lee: Washington Talk (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Massachusetts Historical Society, Bicentennial Symposium 1991-1992 (Box L)
    - Correspondence-- Missouri(Paperback edition) (Box L)
    - Correspondenc--Massachusetts Historical Society 1970-1986 (Box L)
    - Correspondence-Moulton, Harland B. 1952-1991 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--O'Toole, Patricia 1986-1991 (Box L)
    - Correspondence--Oxford University Press 1984-1989 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Society of Colonial Wars Speech 1985-1990 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association 1982-1983 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association (January-August) 1984 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association (September-December) 1984 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association (January-March) 1985 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association (April-June) 1985 (Box M)
    - Correspondence--Southern Historical Association (July-December) 1985 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Stephenson, George M 1951-1958 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Stratford Hall Plantation 1985-1992 (Box N)